It's really coming down, isn't it?
ホントウ よく降るわね
The laundry is never going to dry...
洗濯物が乾かないんだよ
Mr. Bruno.
ブルノさん
Here.
これ
It's to "Angelo Lagusa,"
アンジェロ ラグサってあるけど
but the address is your apartment...
住所があんたの部屋で...
It's yours, then?
あんたのなんだね
本字幕由✿花語&千夏字幕組✿共同製作
He's so creepy.
気持ち悪いね
I can hardly tell if he's alive or dead...
生きてんだか 死んでんだか
Vanetti...
バネッチィ
Night of the Murder
Day 1
殺人之夜
It's really not hot?
本当に熱くない
うん
Yeah.
It's not the wick that's burning.
燃えてるのは芯じゃなくて
It's the paraffin, the stuff the candle's made of.
パラフィンっていう蝋燭の成分だから
芯を摘まんでも...
If you touch the wick—
You do it, then!
じゃあ やってよ
Wow! It really wasn't hot?
すげぇ 熱くないの
Yeah, see?
あぁ ほら
But it really was hot, right?
でも 本当は熱かったでしょう
Not at all.
全然
I'd better get home.
そろそろ帰らなきゃ
Aww!
Let's have cake together first!
一緒にケーキ食べようよ
Maybe next time.
また今度ね
But cake is so good...
ケーキ美味しいのに
What can he do about it?
しょうがないだろ
Hmph... Okay, fine!
チェー じゃあ いいや
Corteo. Share this with your mother, okay?
コルテオ お母さんと一緒に食べてね
And here. I know it's not much...
後 これ 少ないけど...
Thanks... as always.
すみません いつも
いいのよ
It's nothing.
それより お母さんの具合 どう
Anyway, how is your mother doing?
最近は大分いいみたいです
She's been doing a lot better lately, I think.
I see. I'm glad to hear that.
そう ならよかった
See you later!
じゃあね
Goodnight, Luce.
おやすみ ルチェ
Angelo.
アンジェロ
Had you ever put out a candle with your fingers before?
蝋燭 指で消したことあったな
Wow, and it's already April.
もう 四月なのにね
Yeah.
うん
Goodnight.
おやすみ
Or, actually...
じゃなかった
Happy birthday!
誕生日 おめでとう
Don't make a sound, okay?
声出したら 駄目だからね
Right.
あぁ
They're here!
来た
Where are they?
あいつらは
Why not call them and see?
さぁ 呼んでみたら
アンジェロ
Angelo!
ルチェ
Luce!
Where are you?
どこだ
Testa! Open up!
テスター 開けてくれ
It's Vincente!
ヴィンセントだ
Vince?
ヴィンス？
Darn it...
あぁ もう
He'll leave soon.
すぐ帰るさ
You don't come to my house often.
珍しいな うちに来るなんて
Want a drink?
飲むか
No.
いや
I want you to listen calmly.
それより 落ち着いて聞け
The don's been taken out.
ドンがやられた
Orco's men?
オルコの奴らか?
いや
No.
俺さ
Me.
Hush! Keep quiet!
シー 静かに
もうすぐ帰るから
They'll leave soon.
It's to protect the family.
ファミリーを守るためだ
After all he's done for you...
あれだけ世話になっていたが...
You're wrong, Testa.
違うな テスター
You don't understand anything.
お前はなにも分かってない
If you investigated, you'd know how much got back to the Galassias.
ガラッシアにどれだけ流したか 調べれば分かる
もういい 帳簿出せ
Enough. Give me the ledger.
It's not here.
ここにはない
It's at the bank.
銀行に預けた
Give me the ledger! Now!
帳簿を出せ 今すぐ
Please! Stop it!
お願い もうやめて
Elena!
エレナ
Are you okay?
大丈夫?
Luce!
ルーチュ
Mama!
ママ
Don't look!
見ちゃ駄目
Vincente...
ヴィンセント
Spare my child!
この子を助けて
He won't tell anyone, I swear!
誰にも言わない 絶対
So please...
だから...
Elena, listen to me.
エレナ よく聞く
That child will never forget about us,
その子は俺達を決して忘れない
for as long as he lives.
生きてる限り
Mama!
ママ
お願い
Please!
Got anything to wipe up with?
何か拭くもんあんか
We'll look upstairs.
俺たちぁ二階
Nero, you search down here.
ネロ お前は下捜せ
I made cocoa.
ココア 作ったよ
Sorry.
ごめん
I shouldn't have come here.
来ちゃいけなかったのに
It's okay.
大丈夫
They wouldn't chase you this far.
ここまでは追ってこないよ
Sleep a little while, okay?
少し眠りなよ
Angelo.
アヴィリオ
Starting now, you and I are brothers.
たった今から 僕達は兄弟だ
And we always will be.
これからずっと
What a kick!
キックがすげえ
This booze is definitely the next big thing.
やっぱ次に来るのはこの酒だぜ
Right?
なあ
I keep telling you to sell this stuff to the Orco family.
だからオルコファミリの店に卸してやるつってんじゃん
今の三倍の値で売れるぜ
You'd make three times what you're getting now.
I can't stand the mafia.
マフィアは嫌いなんだ
That's rich, coming from a bootlegger.
密造酒作ってるやつがいうセリフかよ
Listen, my brother's working with Fango now.
な 兄貴は今ファンゴさんのとこにいるんだ
知らないよ
What do I care?
He's a guy who just joined the Orco family.
この間オルコファミリに入った人で
They say he's a real psycho.
まじすげえ生かしてんだって
Please leave, Cerotto.
帰ってくれ チェロト
Listen, Corteo...
な コルテオ
How long are you going to stay in this dump?
いつまでもこんなごみ溜めに...
Just go!
帰れよ
Don't blame me for whatever happens.
どうなっても知らねぜ
Did you get the sale?
うまく行ったか
B-Bro...
あ あにき
それが マフィアが嫌いだって...
Actually, he said he hates the mafia—
俺達に酒を卸せ
Sell us the booze.
Gonna sell it to us?
酒を卸すか
N-No...
嫌だ
Stop it!
やめてくれ
Gotta nip the competition in the bud!
商売敵を潰しておかねと
Angelo...
アンジェロー
I made it.
俺が作ったんだ
Try it.
飲んでみてよ
I know it's good.
うまいのは知ってる
Making moonshine isn't actually something I want to do...
本当は密造酒なんて作りたくないんだけとね
I just want to save up money to go to school.
お金を貯めて 学校に行きたいんだ
Angelo...
アンジェロー
Where were you for the past seven years?
七年間 どうしてたの
アヴィリオ ブルーノ 今をそう名乗ってる
Avilio Bruno. That's what I go by now.
Is it okay for you to be back in town?
大丈夫なの この町に帰ってきても
You're tired, right?
疲れてるんだろう
You can use this room.
この部屋を使ってよ
Where's your mother?
おばさんは
Last summer...
去年の夏...
There's no one holding you down, then.
じゃ 誰にも気兼ねしなくていいわけだ
Want to make some money with me?
一緒に一儲けしないか
これを売るんだよ ファミリに
I want to sell this to the family.
僕はファミリと関わりたくないんだ
I don't want to get involved with the family.
Didn't you feel the same—
それはアンジェロだって一緒...
Please, Corteo.
頼むよ コルテオ
A raison d'etre gives a person power.
生きがいは人に力を与え
友情はナイフよりも心強い
Friendship is a more reliable tool than a knife.
We're brothers, right?
俺達 兄弟だろう
That sandbar is called the Island.
あの中州がアイランドだよ
That's probably where it will fetch the highest price.
この辺一番高く売れるのはあそこだと思う
Ever since Prohibition,
禁酒法が出来てから
it's become a haven for the dangerous type.
物騒な奴らが集めてきてさ
But the speakeasies cater to a higher breed of clientele,
でも あそこは俺たちの入れるような
and probably won't let us in...
安いもぐり酒場じゃないよ
They say that church was converted into a bar.
あの教会が酒場になってるんだって
どうだ 悪くねだろう
Well? Not bad, huh?
Brand-name stuff?
ブランの酒だなあ
You bet!
その通り
The cream of the crop, fresh over the border!
国境の向こうから来た絶品中の絶品よ
I've never had better.
こんな旨い酒 飲んだことねえ
I thought you weren't a drinker.
お前は下戸だろうが
知らなねのか
Didn't you know?
You can tell good booze purely from the smell.
いい酒は飲まずに香を嗅ぐんだよ
Take a whiff of your own asshole, then.
けつの穴でも嗅いでろう
I thought the Orco family controlled all the routes over the border.
今 国境のルートはオルコファミリーが抑えてたよな
Are you guys filching off the Orcos?
お前らオルコからくすねたのか
何で分かった
How'd you know?
You've got that look to you—
だがらお前らはそんなナリ...
Mr. Granchio.
グランキオさん
Hey.
Someone swiped a little of our booze.
うちの酒がこそどろに盗まれちまってかな
I'm out looking for it.
探してるんだわ
I don't know squat. Who are you?
知らねな 誰だよお前
You with the Orco Family?
オルコファミリーか?
あぁ ファンゴってんだ
Yeah, I'm Fango.
Where'd you get the booze?
この酒は?
I brought it in.
運んできたんだ
From where?
どこから
あっちからだ
That way.
え 正直なもんじゃねか ボイー
You're honest, ain't ya? Boy...
I'll ask you one more time.
もう一度聞くぜ
Where'd you get the hooch?
この酒はどうした
I want you to buy our booze.
酒を仕入れてほしい
Take a hike.
帰れ
We don't stock bathtub gin made by trash like you.
Bathtub gin:美國禁酒時期,非法入口的酒無法滿足市場需求,
人們在家裡製造的劣質gin被成為bathtub gin
ここにはてめぇらが作るようなバスタブジンはおかねんだ
You brat. Think you're hot stuff, huh?
ガキ 調子乗ってると
Why, you...
この...
Hey, we'll buy it.
俺たちが仕入れよう
Maybe we could stock this after all.
これならうちで出せる
We could even buy direct...
何なら直接仕入れても...
You dumped it out.
お前は捨てたろ
I drank it. Remember?
俺は飲んだ 違うか
Don't get so mad.
そうおこんなよ
Hey, mister. Get me some coffee.
おい おっさん コーヒーくれ
はいよ
Yeah, yeah.
How much per bottle?
一瓶いくらか
3.5.
3.5
話にならない
Out of the question.
How much can you sell us per week?
週にどれぐらい卸せる?
I'll kill you!
ぶっころしてやる
Open. The. Door.
あ け ろ
Uh-oh. Seems the old man's getting the works.
あらら やられてるぞ おっさん
Shut up, anyone can see that.
うるせ 見りゃわかる
What do we do?
どうする
Let's watch for now.
とりあえず様子見
Yeah...
だなぁ
Mind if I take this?
もらってもいいか
このやろう
You son of a...
Sorry to interrupt all the fun!
お楽しみのところ 失礼
The name's Fango.
ファンゴってもんだ
I just joined up with the Orco family.
この間からオルコファミリーでせわんなってる
I've got business with a kid named Nero Vanetti.
ネロ バネッティって奴に用があるんだが
Is he here?
いねえか
ネロ
Nero...
ドン バネッティの息子だ
He's Don Vanetti's son.
Hey, now, don't bring your arguments to the Island.
このアイランドにもめ事を持ち込むな
That's the rule here.
それがここのルールだ
ルール?
Rules!
Yeah, those things are important, huh?
確かに大事だよな
I came here to make sure the rules are being enforced.
俺も今日はそのルールってやつを正しにきた
Because, see,
ついさっき
I just found some booze stolen from us in your parking lot.
その駐車場でうちから盗まれた酒を見つけちまってな
それりゃよかった
Good for you.
なんか言ったか?
You said something?
No.
いや
Now, about Nero Vanetti...
で ネロ バネッティだ
Has that little scamp been in here at all?
その若僧がこの店に立ち寄ってるとか
Hey.
You.
お前だよ
Come here, I said!
来いっつってんだ
You're Nero, right?
ネロだな
No! I'm not Nero!
違う 僕ネロなんかじゃない
Hey!
Any other Neros here?
他にネロはいるか?
See? It's gotta be you.
ほらなぁ やっぱお前じゃねぇか
Bad little boys who steal booze
人の酒を盗む悪い子は
deserve to die.
死刑
俺だ
It's me.
I'm Nero.
俺がネロだ
Oh? Then who's this?
あれ じゃ此奴は
Dunno.
さぁ
んだよ 早く言えよ
Well, speak up sooner.
Okay, new Nero.
じゃ 新しいネロ
Come over here.
こっち来い
おい やるじゃねぇか
Not bad at all.
Let him go.
そいつを放せ
Serpente, do it.
セルペンテ やっちまえ
Slit his throat.
喉を掻っ切れ
こいつに俺はやれねぇよ
This kid can't kill me.
そう 来いよ
That's right. Go on.
Hey! Over here!
おい こっちだ
The counter's iron-plated.
カウンターが鉄板入りだな
ナイスだ おっさん
Nice one, mister.
もう グランキオは逃げたぞ
Granchio's run off.
It's no use!
駄目だ
If he spots you, you're dead.
顔出しだら 蜂の巣だ
弾切れまで待つか?
So we wait for him to run out of ammo?
Hey, Serpente!
おい セルペンテ
Bullets! Bring more bullets!
弾だ そこらへんから弾持って来い
Got it!
了解
We can't fight back with pistols.
うちとも 拳銃じゃ勝負になんねぜ
Don't just watch.
見てないで
Start throwing alcohol at him.
あいつらの周りに酒を投げて
分かった
Got it.
That idiot's playing around.
あの野郎 遊んでやがる
Yeah.
I heard a crazy guy had joined Orco. I guess that's him.
イカれた奴がOrcoに入ったと聞いたが 彼奴か
やっぱりオルコ 本気でやり合う
I guess Orco's gotten serious.
You two, quit messing around!
お前ら なに暢気に
Hey, you guys! Come at me!
ほおりゃ てめぇら かかって来い
よし 出来た
Okay, it's done.
Throw this, then head for the exit!
これを投げたら 出口に向かって
What are you...
一体何を
Just do it!
いいから やれ
熱っ
Hot!
Tigre!
ティグレ
Hey!
おい
Wake up!
しっかりしろ
Damn, what a day.
やれやれ 今日はなんて日だ
It was pretty fun, though.
でも面白かったじゃねぇか
先は ありがとう
Thanks for before.
The stuff candles are made of...
蝋燭の成分は
Paraffin?
パラフィン?
Yeah.
If you liquefy paraffin, then mix it with water...
パラフィンは液化させてから水に混ぜると
It'll blow, just like you saw.
ボン あの通りさ
Thanks to that, we can't go back there for a while.
おかげで あそこには当分近づけねよな
Your booze was good, though.
それにしても お前らの酒は旨かった
It'll make us lots of money.
あれは稼げるぜ
Look, that's the Vanettis' playhouse.
ほら あれがVanettisの劇場だ
It's something, huh?
大したもんだろう
Can't wait to show it to the don when it's finished.
早く完成した姿をドンに見せてやりてぇな
It looks so out of place in this town.
この町には不釣り合いだ
Hey.
なぁ
That man, Nero...
ネロって男は
Was he there?
あそこにいたのか
Yeah.
ネロ バネッティは...
Nero Vanetti...
is me.
俺だ